Hello English learners.
各位英语学习者，大家好。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we have a special lesson for all our sci-fi or science fiction fans.
今天，我们为所有科幻迷准备了一节特别的课程。
Yes, and actually one special user was the inspiration for this lesson.
是的，实际上，一位特别的用户给了我们这节课的灵感。
Wolfgang.
Wolfgang。
Exactly.
没错。
This one is for you.
这节课是为你准备的。
Well, sci-fi is very popular, Star Trek, Star Wars.
嗯，科幻很受欢迎，比如《星际迷航》、《星球大战》。
Yep.
对。
And well, there are some really interesting words that maybe you wouldn't use in real life or in normal circumstances.
而且，有些非常有趣的词，你可能在现实生活中或正常情况下不会用到。
But you do want to understand these movies or why they say these words, right?
但你确实想理解这些电影，或者他们为什么说这些词，对吧？
So we're going to look at some sci-fi language in this lesson.
所以这节课我们将学习一些科幻语言。
But before we start, let's look at Vocabulary Preview.
但在开始之前，我们先来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
And in Vocabulary Preview today, we have one phrase only.
今天的词汇预览，我们只有一个短语。
That's right.
没错。
Unidentified spacecraft.
不明航天器。
Okay.
好的。
So unidentified.
所以“不明”的意思是。
You don't know which one it is.
你不知道是哪一个。
You don't know the name.
你不知道名字。
Yeah.
对。
You don't know the identity.
你不知道身份。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
And a spacecraft.
而“航天器”。
A spacecraft is a vehicle that travels in space.
航天器是一种在太空中飞行的交通工具。
Okay.
好的。
Also known as a spaceship.
也叫宇宙飞船。
That's right.
没错。
Actually, this is interesting because you know the word UFO.
实际上，这很有趣，因为你知道UFO这个词。
Yes.
是的。
That comes from...
它来自……
Unidentified flying object.
不明飞行物。
Exactly.
没错。
So unidentified spacecraft, an unknown vehicle flying in space.
所以不明航天器，就是太空中一个未知的飞行器。
Right.
对。
A UFO.
一个UFO。
Have you ever seen a UFO?
你见过UFO吗？
No.
没有。
Oh.
哦。
That's too bad.
太可惜了。
Have you?
你呢？
Of course.
当然见过。
Hasn't anyone?
难道不是所有人都见过吗？
All right.
好吧。
Well, I think the people in our dialogue may or may not have seen a UFO.
嗯，我觉得我们对话里的人可能见过也可能没见过UFO。
So why don't we take a listen?
那我们不如来听一听？
They are breaking through.
他们正在突破防线。
Set your blasters to full power.
把你们的爆能枪调到最大功率。
Good job.
干得好。
Search the ship.
搜索飞船。
She's got to be in here somewhere.
她一定在这儿的某个地方。
Bring her to me.
把她带到我面前。
Lord Hater, we have a survivor here.
憎恨领主，我们这里有一个幸存者。
Where is she?
她在哪儿？
Don't make me destroy you.
别逼我毁了你。
Tell me where she is.
告诉我她在哪儿。
Not so fast.
别急。
She will no longer be your prisoner.
她不再是你的囚犯了。
It's time you and I settled this once and for all.
是时候我们俩彻底了结这件事了。
You are unwise to think you can defeat me.
你太不明智了，竟以为能打败我。
You know nothing of the power of the obscure side.
你对黑暗面的力量一无所知。
We will stop you.
我们会阻止你的。
Lord Hater, we have an unidentified spacecraft taking off from the rear dock.
憎恨领主，我们有一艘不明航天器从后船坞起飞了。
They somehow managed to escape our tractor beam.
他们不知怎么设法逃脱了我们的牵引光束。
After them.
追他们。
They're accelerating towards the speed of light.
他们正在加速接近光速。
We lost them, sir.
我们跟丢了，长官。
Okay, so a really cool Lord Hater, huh?
好的，一个很酷的憎恨领主，是吧？
The music and everything.
还有音乐什么的。
Well, you may have noticed that it's similar to a certain movie out there.
嗯，你可能注意到了，这跟某部电影很像。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I mean, it seems quite original to me.
我是说，对我来说它似乎挺原创的。
But everything for educational purposes.
但一切都是为了教育目的。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so we saw some words that were maybe a little bit difficult.
好的，我们看到了一些可能有点难的词。
So let's take a look at these now in Language Takeaway.
所以现在我们在“语言要点”里来看看这些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, I guess in the dialogue, the bad guys were breaking through.
嗯，我想在对话中，坏蛋们正在突破防线。
Breaking through.
突破防线。
In the simple present, it would be?
一般现在时是？
To break through.
突破。
Okay, break through.
好的，突破。
And what does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Well, let's listen to some examples to help us find out.
嗯，我们来听一些例子，帮助我们弄清楚。
Example 1.
例子1。
After 15 minutes, the workers broke through the wall and rescued everyone from the fire.
15分钟后，工人们破墙而入，救出了火灾中的所有人。
Example 2.
例子2。
He is such a good player.
他是个非常棒的球员。
He broke through the entire defense.
他突破了整个防线。
Example 3.
例子3。
They are breaking through our impenetrable wall.
他们正在突破我们坚不可摧的墙。
Run!
快跑！
All right, so it's kind of like to enter by force somewhere.
好的，所以这有点像强行进入某个地方。
Yeah, to maybe break some glass and come into a room or something like that.
对，可能是打破玻璃进入房间之类的。
Break through.
突破。
Yeah.
对。
All right, so Lord Hater had a fight with his enemy and he said he wants to settle this.
好的，所以憎恨领主和他的敌人打了一架，他说他想了结这件事。
To settle this.
了结这件事。
Settle.
了结。
So what do you do when you settle something?
那么当你了结某事时，你做了什么？
Well, when you settle something is you end a fight or a dispute.
嗯，当你了结某事时，就是结束一场打斗或争端。
Or an argument.
或者一场争论。
Or an argument or a problem.
或者一场争论或问题。
Yeah, when you settle an argument, does everyone always agree?
对，当你了结一场争论时，大家总是同意吗？
No, not always, right?
不，不总是，对吧？
Right.
对。
Sometimes you are forced to agree.
有时你被迫同意。
Okay.
好的。
Not everyone agrees, but you have no other choice.
不是每个人都同意，但你别无选择。
So it's a little bit different from reaching an agreement because there's usually a winner and a loser.
所以这和达成协议有点不同，因为通常有赢家和输家。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
Well, now another very popular word and within sci-fi is this word tractor beam.
嗯，现在另一个非常流行且属于科幻的词是“牵引光束”。
Tractor beam.
牵引光束。
A tractor beam.
Tractor beam.
牵引光束。
Now, I'm not sure if this really exists in real life.
现在，我不确定这在现实生活中是否真的存在。
Well, I've never heard of it.
嗯，我从没听说过。
But a tractor beam in sci-fi movies is like this invisible force that grabs an object and doesn't let it escape and brings it towards another spaceship.
但在科幻电影中，牵引光束就像一种无形的力量，抓住一个物体，不让它逃脱，并把它拉向另一艘宇宙飞船。
So it's like almost like a rope that you can't see.
所以它就像一根看不见的绳子。
Right, and it brings it in.
对，把它拉进来。
So the spaceship managed to escape their tractor beam.
所以那艘宇宙飞船设法逃脱了他们的牵引光束。
Okay, I think that is definitely not true.
好的，我觉得那肯定不是真的。
Well, maybe, I don't know.
嗯，也许吧，我不知道。
But in sci-fi you will always hear this tractor beam.
但在科幻中你总会听到这个牵引光束。
Okay.
好的。
Now, let's move on to our final word.
现在，我们来看最后一个词。
The spaceship was accelerating towards the speed of light.
宇宙飞船正在加速接近光速。
Accelerating.
加速。
To accelerate.
That's right.
没错。
So that means to increase speed, right?
所以那意味着增加速度，对吧？
Yeah, to go faster.
对，就是开得更快。
To go faster.
开得更快。
So if you are in your car.
所以如果你在车里。
You want to accelerate so you can pass another car.
你想加速以便超过另一辆车。
Okay.
好的。
Or even when you stop at a red light and it turns green.
或者甚至当你停在红灯前，灯变绿时。
You got to accelerate.
你得加速。
Okay, to accelerate.
好的，加速。
Let's listen to our dialogue again and then we'll come back and take a look at some of the phrases that came up in this dialogue.
让我们再听一遍我们的对话，然后回来看看对话中出现的一些短语。
Lord Hater, we have an unidentified spacecraft taking off from the rear dock.
憎恨领主，我们有一艘不明航天器从后船坞起飞了。
They somehow managed to escape our tractor beam.
他们不知怎么设法逃脱了我们的牵引光束。
After them.
追他们。
They're accelerating towards the speed of light.
他们正在加速接近光速。
We lost them, sir.
我们跟丢了，长官。
Well, great.
嗯，很好。
I think that's a little bit more clear this time.
我想这次更清楚一些了。
But like Marco said, I want to look at now some phrases that you might hear in a sci-fi context.
但就像Marco说的，我现在想看看一些你可能在科幻语境中听到的短语。
The first phrase that we can take a look at and maybe it looks a little bit strange.
第一个我们可以看看的短语，可能看起来有点奇怪。
He said she will no longer be your prisoner.
他说她不再是你的囚犯了。
No longer be.
不再是。
So what does he mean by no longer?
那么他说的“不再”是什么意思？
Anymore.
再也不。
Anymore, right?
再也不，对吧？
Yeah, so you will not be my prisoner anymore.
对，所以你不再是我的囚犯了。
Okay, so how would I use it in this form?
好的，那我怎么用这个形式呢？
No longer be.
不再是。
You've always got to use it in the future tense.
你总是得用在将来时态里。
Okay, so she'll no longer be your prisoner.
好的，所以她不再是你的囚犯了。
I will no longer be your employee.
我不再是你的员工了。
Okay, or I can say I will no longer be your boyfriend.
好的，或者我可以说我不再是你的男朋友了。
Okay, so it's always will no longer be.
好的，所以总是“将不再是”。
It's always in the future.
总是用在将来时。
Okay.
好的。
One more thing, Marco.
还有一件事，Marco。
Is this quite commonly used or maybe a little bit formal?
这个常用吗，还是有点正式？
I think it's a little bit formal and it's very, I don't know, to a certain point poetic.
我觉得有点正式，而且非常，怎么说呢，有点诗意。
Yeah, which I think is why we hear it a little bit more often in sci-fi movies.
对，我想这就是为什么我们在科幻电影中更常听到它。
All right, so no longer be.
好的，所以“不再是”。
What about our next phrase?
那我们的下一个短语呢？
You know nothing of the power of the obscure side.
你对黑暗面的力量一无所知。
Okay, you know nothing of.
好的，你一无所知。
You know nothing of.
你一无所知。
So again, it's very poetic.
所以同样，这非常诗意。
Yeah, basically meaning you don't know about.
对，基本上意思是你不了解。
You don't know about.
你不了解。
Yeah.
对。
So again, let's take a look at how you would use it.
所以同样，我们来看看你怎么用它。
You know nothing of and then.
你一无所知，然后接……
Science fiction.
科幻小说。
You know nothing of science fiction.
你对科幻小说一无所知。
Yeah.
对。
Very good.
非常好。
So you would use a noun afterwards.
所以后面要跟一个名词。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, so interesting phrases.
好的，有趣的短语。
Again, formal and probably quite often used in science fiction movies.
同样，很正式，可能经常用在科幻电影里。
But now you can understand when they use some of these words that maybe are a little bit difficult and very common in these types of movies.
但现在你能理解他们用的一些词了，这些词可能有点难，但在这类电影中很常见。
Now let's go to our last phrase.
现在我们来看最后一个短语。
And this one actually can be used in many different circumstances.
而这个实际上可以在很多不同的情况下使用。
Let's settle this once and for all.
让我们一劳永逸地解决这个问题。
Okay, so we saw the word settle already.
好的，我们之前已经见过“settle”这个词了。
Now let's settle this once and for all.
现在让我们一劳永逸地解决这个问题。
Once and for all.
一劳永逸。
So what does that mean?
那是什么意思呢？
Finally.
最终。
That's right, forever.
没错，永远。
Okay, so once and for all, forever.
好的，所以“once and for all”就是“永远”。
So why don't we listen to some other examples of how we can use this phrase once and for all in different contexts.
那我们不如听一些其他例子，看看这个短语“once and for all”在不同语境中怎么用。
Example one.
例子一。
I'm fed up with arguing about this.
我受够了为这事争吵。
Let's just settle the argument once and for all.
我们就一劳永逸地解决这个争论吧。
Example two.
例子二。
He claims his photographs prove once and for all that UFOs do exist.
他声称他的照片一劳永逸地证明了UFO确实存在。
Example three.
例子三。
I told him once and for all that I don't want to be his girlfriend anymore.
我一劳永逸地告诉他，我不想再做他女朋友了。
Okay, so now I think it's clear.
好的，现在我觉得清楚了。
We've seen a lot of words.
我们看到了很多单词。
We've seen a lot of phrases.
我们看到了很多短语。
Let's listen to our dialogue one more time.
让我们再听一遍我们的对话。
They are breaking through.
他们正在突破。
Set your blasters to full power.
把你们的爆能枪调到最大功率。
Excellent job.
干得好。
Search the ship.
搜查飞船。
She's got to be in here somewhere.
她一定在这儿的某个地方。
Bring her to me.
把她带到我面前。
Lord Hager, we have a survivor here.
哈格大人，我们这里有一个幸存者。
Where is she?
她在哪儿？
Don't make me destroy you.
别逼我毁了你。
Tell me where she is.
告诉我她在哪儿。
Not so fast.
别急。
She will no longer be your prisoner.
她不再是你的囚犯了。
I'm sure you and I settled this once and for all.
我确信你和我已经一劳永逸地解决了这件事。
You are unwise to think you can defeat me.
你以为能打败我，真是太不明智了。
You know nothing of the power of the obscure side.
你对黑暗面的力量一无所知。
We will stop you.
我们会阻止你的。
Lord Hager, we have an unidentified spacecraft taking off from the rear dock.
哈格大人，有一艘不明飞船从后码头起飞了。
They somehow managed to escape our tractor beam.
他们不知怎么逃脱了我们的牵引光束。
After them.
追他们。
They're accelerating towards the speed of light.
他们正在加速到光速。
We lost them, sir.
我们跟丢了，长官。
Okay, so are you a big sci-fi fan?
好的，你是个科幻迷吗？
I think as you can tell, no.
我想你也能看出来，不是。
Actually, I've seen some of the Star Wars movies, but everyone that I've watched, I've fallen asleep in the middle of.
其实我看过一些《星球大战》电影，但每次看，我都在中间睡着了。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, even in the movie theater.
是啊，甚至在电影院里。
I fell asleep in the movie theater watching Star Wars.
我在电影院看《星球大战》时睡着了。
Wow, was it too boring?
哇，太无聊了吗？
It was too boring.
太无聊了。
You're not really into the fantasy side?
你不怎么喜欢奇幻题材吗？
No, the whole time I'm sitting there going, this cannot happen.
不，我全程坐在那儿想，这不可能发生。
Well, that's why it's called science fiction, right?
嗯，所以它才叫科幻小说，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
But it is interesting to some people, and well, behind Star Wars, there is a huge culture.
但对有些人来说它很有趣，而且，《星球大战》背后有庞大的文化。
Even some people know some of the languages or symbols that are used in it, or the names of some of the robots and models of spacecraft.
甚至有些人知道里面用的一些语言或符号，或者一些机器人和飞船型号的名字。
Well, maybe we'll have to come up with Star Wars pods.
嗯，也许我们得推出《星球大战》播客了。
Exactly.
没错。
Well, that's all for today, guys.
好了，今天就到这里，各位。
I hope you enjoyed our lesson.
希望你们喜欢我们的课程。
And of course, if you have questions or comments, you can leave them in the comments section on our website, EnglishPod.com.
当然，如果你们有问题或评论，可以留在我们网站EnglishPod.com的评论区。
Well, thanks for listening, you guys, and until next time, goodbye.
嗯，谢谢收听，各位，下次再见，拜拜。